Students:OK.So as many of you may have already heard,
大家可能已经听说了
the American Cancer Society Fund Raiser Relay for Life
美国防癌协会生命接力募捐活动
is this Friday day night at Gordon Track.
定于今周五晚在Gordon田径场举行
The event increases awarenesses
本次活动旨在引起公众关注
and raises money for cancer education,research and treatment.
并为防癌宣传 研究 治疗筹集资金
It's not too late to get involved either.
我们随时欢迎大家的参与
By registering online,donating to a participant
大家可以在线注册，为参赛者捐款
or showing upat the event to see what it's all about.
或者出席观看赛事 了解活动
At the event,we will have Root Beer Beirut,
本次活动为大家准备了啤酒游戏
Accapella and band performances,and Miss Relay pageant,
无伴奏合唱 乐队表演 接力赛小姐选举
and movies and games
还有电影和游戏
and all the wild people will be walking last round the track,
最后大家都会沿着跑道走一圈
remember those lost,
藉此缅怀被癌症夺去生命的人
celebrate survivors and hope for a future here.
为癌症生还者庆祝 并展望未来
Look up for emails
请大家查看邮件
and check out our Facebook group for more information.
浏览我们的Foocbook小组 了解更多
I hope to see you all there.Thanks.
希望到时能见到大家，谢谢
[Applause]
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar: Hi.Good morning.
大家早上好
We are going to pick up where we are left of last time.
我们接着讲上节课没讲完的内容
But before we do,a few of you came to me after the class
开始讲之前 上节课后有同学来找我
and asked about alternative form of exercise.
问我有没有其他的运动选择
So the study that I gave and also what you read-
我上次讲的研究 希望大家也去看看
the article by Callaghan and others,
就是Callaghan等人写的那篇文章
is mostly about aerobic exercise.
里面侧重讲的是有氧运动
And as I mentioned earlier,
我之前也提过
this is about moderate intensity workout,
做这运动的目的是缓和高强度运动
which would mean if you want to work with pulse about 70 percent,
做这种运动 你会达到最大心率的70%
between 65 and 75 percent of your maximum heart rate-
大约在最大心率的65%到75%之间
again you just Google heart rate exercise,
大家搜索心率运动
you'll immediately get all the tables that you need.
就能马上得到想查的各种心率表
But that's one form of exercise.
这是其中一种运动形式
Some of you asked,
有些同学问
"what about weight training? What about interval training?"
"举重训练行不行 间歇训练行不行?"
So sprints and stop.Sprints and stop.
快跑 休息 再快跑 再休息
Something that you know the crew team does often,
这种是划艇队经常做的训练
athletes do often.
运动员经常做的训练
What about this form?
这些运动行不行?
The reason why I didn't bring it up explicitly in the lecture is
我上节课没有专门提出
because the jury is still out on the different forms of exercise.
是因为目前对其他的运动还没有定论
But let me tell you
我可以告诉大家
what are some of the trends that we see in research.
目前在研究中发现的一些趋势
Right now it seems that
目前看来
if there's only one form of exercise that you do,
如果你只能做一种运动
the best bank for the buck,
那么最佳选择
best value for your time would be aerobic exercise.
时间最花得其所的是有氧运动
3,ideally 4 times,30 minutes of aerobic exercise a week.
理想地每周三四次半小时的有氧运动
That's at minimum.
这是最低要求
However,however,
但是
if you can also do weight training and supplement the physic...
如果你还能做举重训练以补充
the aerobic exercise,that's terrific.That's great.
有氧运动 那也很好
Twice a week,3 times of weight training is great,
一周两三次举动训练非常好
especially as you get older.
尤其是年纪大了以后
That...Weight training contributes more.
举重训练更加有用
But also at a very young age,weight training is good.
但在年轻时 举重训练也很好
However,it is not a replacement for aerobic exercise.
但是 它不能代替有氧运动
It hasn't shown to have the same psychological effect
研究发现它改善心理健康的效果
as aerobic exercise does.
不如有氧运动
The other form of exercise and it has been studied-
另外一种运动 在经过研究后…
again these are all tentative results;
我要重申 这些都是初步结果
there've been pilot studies about it.
有人对这种运动做过初步研究
The ends,
最后结果
the sample sizes are not large enough yet to say definitively,
因为样本不足 暂时无法下确切结论
just like we can say about aerobic exercise,
但我们可以确切地说有氧运动
it has similar effect
产生的效果能媲美
to some of our most powerful psychiatric drugs.
一些强效精神病药物
That's definitive- there are tons of studies on it
这个结论是确切的 有大量研究来支持
ever since Babyak in 2000 as well as before.
包括Babyak2000年以来的研究 以及之前的
But another form of exercise that has begun to be studied
另一种开始被研究的运动
with some very promising results is interval training.
得出可喜的结果 那就是间歇运动
Interval training would be,say,running at,
间歇运动就是 以跑步为例子
between 90 and 95 percent of your maximum heart rate.
达到最大心率的90%到95%
So if you are 20,your maximum heart rate would be,would be 200,
如果你20岁 你最大心率就是200
because it's 220 minus your age.
计算公式是220减去年龄
Then you need to be running at around at 180 to 190 pulse rate,
所以你跑步的心率要达到180到190
which is hard,which is tough,
强度非常高
which you can't do for a very long time.
不能持续很长时间
But doing it for as little as 30 seconds up to a minute
但如果能持续30秒到一分钟
and then resting,
然后休息
letting your heart rate go back down to 60 percent
让你的心率下降到最大心率的60%
of its maximum say 120,and then doing another interval.
也就是120 然后重复这个间歇运动
That has been shown with pilot studies only
有初步研究表明这种运动
to have remarkable effects.
能产生显著效果
In fact,often more powerful than aerobic exercise on its own,
通常效果甚至比单纯做有氧运动更大
and lasts for even longer- the effect.
而且持续时间更长
So- again,
所以 再说回来
I did not introduce it officially as part of the class,
我没有在课堂上正式介绍这种运动
but since many of you asked,I am introducing it.
但很多同学问起 所以现在介绍一下
Because I want to introduce you only things
因为我只想给大家介绍
that are with very robust results.
那些有确切结论的运动
John Ratey talks about this.
John Ratey也谈过这种运动
And I'll talk a little bit about John Ratey in a minute.
我等一下会讲John Ratey
He's the Harvard Medical psychatrist
他是哈佛医学院的精神医生
who is probably the leading proponent in research
可以说他是一个前沿的倡导者
in the area of exercise and mental health.
在研究运动和精神健康这个领域
And he himself- even though the results are still tentative,
他本身…虽然目前的结果是初步的
he introduces two interval trainings a week.
但他一周会做两次间歇运动
So in addition to working out six days a week,
除了一周做六天运动以外
two of them include full out sprinting,rest,
其中两天还会做全速短跑 休息
full out sprinting,rest.
全速短跑 休息
And what they've shown was that even less time than 30 minutes,
研究表明即使没有做够30分钟
you can get the same effect,
但还能得到同等的效果
the same psychological effect and even better.
同等的甚至更好的心理效果
What I do twice a week: I introduce interval training.
我一周也会做两次间歇运动
So for example,
所以 举个例子
this morning when I was on my trampoline,I did it for 30 minutes.
今天早上我在蹦床上跳了30分钟
And out of the 30 minutes,there were 4 sprints.
在这30分钟里 我还做了4个短跑
Indeed.(Laughter)
没错
You don't believe that I do trampoline,do you?
你们不相信我会跳蹦床 是吧?
I'll videotape it and I'll...Maybe not.Maybe not.
我下次拍下来 还是不要了
So 4 sessions of sprints,and I have my heart monitor on,
4次短跑 我戴着心率监测仪
going all way- for me it's about 165 heart rate,
快速跑一段 我的心率大约是165
between 165 and 170,and then resting,going back to about 110,
165到170之间 然后休息 下降到110
which is less than 60 percent of my maximum,
少于我最大心率的60%
and then doing it four times.
如此重复四次
And for the rest of the 30 minutes,
这30分钟里其余的时间
I just do moderate aerobic exercise.
我只做缓和的有氧运动
So I also introduce the interval training.
所以我也做间歇运动
The weight training I do less of,because I get that from Yoga-
举重训练就比较少做 因为我做瑜伽时
a lot of the strengthening exercises.
就有这种加强体能的效果
The most important thing though that
但最重要的一点是
I do want to say about interval training
我想说 间歇运动
is that, especially for perfectionists,
特别是对于完美主义者来说
it's very easy to over-train.
很容易导致训练过度
You don't want to get to your maximum heart rate
大家最好不要达到最大心率
and keep it there for a long time,even if you can.
并且持续一段长时间 即使你做得来
More does not necessarily mean better.
更多并不意味着更好
Again,unless you are training for Olympics,
再说一次 除非你是备战奥运
in which case you do want to get to
这种情况下有时你就要达到
100 percent of your maximum heart rate at times,
100%的最高心率
for maximum health you want to get to 90 percent,
想练出最健康的身体 达到90%…
maximum 95 percent of your maximum heart rate,
最大心率的95%就行了
which is why a heart rate monitor can help so much.
所以戴上心率监测仪就很有用
Because it can tell you when you are working too hard
因为它能告诉你 运动是否强度太大
or when it's too easy.
或者强度不足
Bottom line: variety is good for exercise.
总之 换换花样有助于运动
If you can introduce dancing,it's great exercise.
你可以跳舞 这也是好运动
If you can introduce,once in a while working in the gym,
你可以 偶尔去健身室健身
once in a while playing basketball,
偶尔打篮球
rowing- the more variety,the better.
划艇 花样越多越好
But the foundation: at least we,ideally 4 times a week,
只要保证 至少对我们来说 一周四次
30 minutes of aerobic exercise.
一次30分钟的有氧运动
So we stopped last time with overcoming barriers.
上节课我们讲到克服障碍
And some of the barriers are that
其中一些障碍包括
it's difficult there are some pain associated with it,
伴随运动而来的疼痛 使运动更难了
even if you are at 70 percent of your heart rate.
即使你只达到最大心率的70%
It's still uncomfortable.
运动引起不适
And ways to deal with it is at least as you get into it,
克服不适的最简单方法就是进入状态
cause very often we enter the zone when we start to run,
因为通常我们跑步进入一种状态后
we don't feel the difficulty any more.
我们就感受不到不适了
But at least the beginning is important.
但必须开了头才行
Have social support to divide and conquer,to build gradually,
找别人来支持你克服困难 慢慢适应
and to have distracters,such as TV,and your MP3,
用一些东西分散注意力 例如电视 MP3
and whatever it is.
能分散注意力就行了
Another barrier- and this one is,
另一个障碍
unfortunately very common here on campus,
很不幸 这个障碍在校园很普遍
is just we don't have time.
那就是我们没有时间
You know in high school,
大家知道 在高中
I do give a lot of talks in high schools,and
我经常去高中演讲
one of the things that I see there is that students generally,
我注意到的其中一件事是 通常
in many high schools actually have to be part of a team.
很多高中要求学生参加团队活动
They have to,in addition to doing physical exercise,PE,
他们除了体育课做运动以外
they also have to be part of a team.
还要参加团队活动
So they get not enough,but more exercise,
所以他们运动得更多 虽然还是不够
whereas one of the first things that go in college,
但是我们读大学第一件放弃的事
especially or only for students who do not play on the team,
尤其是那些不参加团队活动的学生
one of the first things that go is exercise.
我们放弃的第一件事是运动
I don't have time.I have so many things that I want to do.
我没有时间 我有很多事要做
It's a new world.
大学是一个新世界
Well,it's also the first things that goes during exam period,
在考试期间 大家也首先就放弃运动
because I'm so stressed.
因为我压力太大了
I have so many things to do.
我有太多事要做了
Well,it should be the last thing to go.
其实 最不能放弃的是运动
It should be the last thing to go.
最不能放弃的是运动
Why? Because it is an investment.
为什么?因为它是一项投资
You may be losing the 45 minutes.
虽然你失去了45分钟
You know,
你知道
working out for 30 minutes and showering after which I recommend.
运动30分钟 之后洗个澡　我推荐大家这么做
You may lose that 45 minutes.
虽然你失去了45分钟
But you'll gain so much more.It's such a good investment.
但你获得了更多 这时间花得其所
Why? Because your memory actually gets better when you exercise.
为什么?因为做运动 记忆力提高
So you'll get more buck for the bank in terms of time you study;
所以你更能充分利用学习时间
your creativity levels go up; your concentration,
你的创造力提高了 精神更集中
whether you have ADD or not,especially if you have
不管你是否有多动症 有就更要运动了
or you have a tendency toward ADD or ADHD,
或者你有患多动症的趋势
but even for people without it,
即使对于没有多动症的人来说
concentration goes up significantly.
运动也能大大提高注意力集中
Energy levels go up significantly.So it's a very good investment.
活力显著提高 所以这时间花得其所
Remember I told you the story
大家还记得我讲过
when I stopped exercising at the end of the squash season?
壁球赛季末我停止运动的事吗?
And suddenly I said,"oh I have so much time."
突然我觉得我有了很多时间
And I ended up getting so much less done.
但我完成的工作反而少了
A,because I don't have the rituals;
第一因为我的生活规律打乱了
and B,because I wasn't as focused,
第二因为我注意力没那么集中了
I wasn't as creative,I wasn't as energized.
我创造力下降了 活力下降了
It should be the last thing to go,especially,
最不能放弃的是运动
especially during a stressful period such as exam period.
尤其是在考试期间这种压力大的时候
One way to overcome the time commitment again
克服时间不足这个问题
is not relying on self-discipline.
不能靠自律
We have established that before;
我们之前已经讲过了
we saw the research- we have a limited amount of self-discipline.
我们看过那个研究 人的自律是有限的
Create rituals where,
我们要自己形成规律
say,3 mornings during the week you'll do it;
例如一周中有三个早上做运动
or if a good time for you is the afternoon or evening,
如果下午晚上才有空 那也行
but have a ritual around it.
形成一个时间规律
Another barrier to exercising regularly-
另一个阻碍定期运动的障碍
this is an interesting one and often overlooked
是一个有趣但经常被忽视的障碍
but extremely powerful- and that is the subconscious barrier.
这个障碍非常强大 潜意识障碍
Nathaniel Branden talks about this
Nathaniel Branden谈过这点
and I talked about it a little bit in my book,quoting him.
我在我的书中也略谈过 引用了他的话
He talks about self-esteem and
他谈到自尊
part of self-esteem is the notion that we are worthy of happiness
自尊隐含了一个概念:我们值得拥有幸福
The notion of being worthy of happiness.
值得拥有幸福
And when you ask people,"are you worthy of happiness?"
当你问别人"你值得拥有幸福吗?"
Most people would say,"yes." But if you ask the subconscious,
大部人会说"值得" 但在潜意识中
very often,for many people,it's "no",
通常很多人都会说"不值得"
whether it's because of the voice that we heard in the past
可能因为脑袋里有一把声音说"不值得"
from teachers,educators,parents,significant adults,
因为过去老师 教育工作者 父母 重要的大人
society at large by comparing us to unrealistic models.
社会大众都要我们向不现实的榜样看齐
But very often we have this voice,the subconscious level that
所以通常在我们潜意识里有一把声音说
"we are not really worthy of happiness".
"我不值得拥有幸福"
And that is a barrier; that stops us from becoming happier.
这是一个障碍 使我们无法更快乐
Now one of the things that we know of exercise is that
我们知道运动的其中一个作用就是
it's one of the- if not the most power drug for making us happier
可以说它是让我们变幸福的最强效药物
Now I know that exercise makes me happier; it makes me feel good.
我知道运动使人幸福 使人感觉良好
But if my subconscious thinks that
但如果我的潜意识认为
I'm unworthy of these feelings,unworthy of being happy,
我不值得拥有这些感觉 不值得幸福
it may in fact stop me from exercising.
它可能阻止我运动
Why? Because remember,
为什么?因为 大家回忆一下
mind doesn't like when there is an inconsistency
意识不喜欢
between what's inside and what's outside.
潜意识与外界不一致
And if what's inside is saying "shouldn't be happy"
如果我潜意识认为"不应该快乐"
then I try to match it to what's inside.
我就会听从我的潜意识
And I don't exercise.
我就不会运动
Because if I do exercise,then there will be a disconnect-
因为我运动的话 就会与潜意识不一致
I'll be happier than I think I'm worthy of.
我会比潜意识认为的更幸福
There's a lot of research on this.
在这个问题上有过很多研究
For example,by psychologist Bill Swann,
例如 心理学家Bill Swann
who talks about self-confirmation theory,
讲过自我确认理论
which is a very powerful force within us.
这是我们意识里一股很强大的力量
There's a self-enhancement,
我们意识里有自我提高
that we want to appear good in other people's eyes,in our eyes,
我们想在别人和自己眼里表现出好的一面
but there is a counter-force,which is self-confirmation
但还有一股反作用力 就是自我确认
where we want to confirm whatever we think about ourselves.
我们想确认对自己的了解是否属实
And if we think we are not worthy of happiness,
如果我们认为自己不值得幸福
we very often not do things that actually make us happy.
通常我们就不会做让自己幸福的事
We see it in other areas- in relationships,for example.
在其他方面也存在 例如在恋情中
If I think I'm unworthy of a wonderful partner,
如果我认为我不值得拥有好伴侣
of being happy in relationships,
不值得在恋情中得到幸福
very often I'll often inadvertently subconscious working here,
通常我就会在潜意识里
jeopardize the relationship
破坏这段恋情
and look for things that are not working,actively,
积极寻找恋情中不顺利的地方
subconsciously look for ways of hurting the relationship.
潜意识中寻找方法伤害这段恋情
So we need to be aware of the subconscious level.
所以我们需要注意这些潜意识力量
And very much it applies to whether or not we exercise.
通常它能影响我们会不会去做运动
So what do we do with this? A best thing to do is to just do it.
我们该拿它怎么办?最好的办法就是运动
Again,ritualize it.
再一次说回来 把它规律化
Not analyze it too much.Just go ahead and exercise.
不要分析太多 尽管去运动就行了
You know 3,4 times a week is good for you,just do it.
你知道一周三四次运动对你有益 尽管去做
And again it's the five-minute take-off that
再一次说到 即想即做法
subconscious mind will try to tell you,
潜意识会告诉你
"don't do it.You don't have the time.There are other things.
"不要做 你没时间 还有别的事要做
You'll do it tomorrow.Next week you'll start the regime."
你明天再做 你下周再开始定期运动"
The subconscious mind is very smart in its attempt,and
为了达到目的 潜意识会很聪明地
will do anything that it can almost to create this congruency.
用尽各种方法 几乎能使你的行动听从潜意识
When you go out and exercise and you show yourself,
当你出去运动时 你就让自己看到
"yes I'm worthy of happiness."
"是的 我值得拥有幸福"
Very often the subconscious mind will follow suit.
通常潜意识就会听从这个想法
So just do it.
所以尽管去运动
The second thing is recognize.This is on the cognitive level.
第二个是认识 这是认知层面的
Recognize how important physical exercise is.
认识运动的重要性
Remember what Martin Seligman said,"we mostly focus on neck up"-
大家回忆Martin Seligman说的"大部分人都专注于脖子以上"
and we do it as psychologists,
心理学家是这样
we do it as students in academic institution,
学术机构里的学生是这样
especially in a place like this.
尤其是在这样的学校里
So much about thinking and cognition.
大过专注于思考和认知
That's how you got here.That's how you were successful.
你们也正因此才能考上哈佛 才能成功
But it's no less important to think about neck down.
但专注于脖子以下 也同样重要
In fact,the mind alone can only take us so far
事实上 要获得幸福 脑袋的作用
when it comes to happiness,which is why I told you
是有限的 所以我要告诉大家
if I were a therapist,a pre-requisite for me to treat people
如果我是心理医生 我治人的第一件事就是
would be to have them exercise regularly.
要求他们运动
Because I don't want to fight nature.
因为我不想违抗自然
I want to work with nature and build on it.
我想借助自然的力量来治人
Exercise in many ways
很大程度上 运动
is the "unsung hero" of the psychological interventions.
是心理治疗中的"无名英雄"
It helps on so many levels.
它在很多方面都发挥了作用
John Ratey- mentioned him;
John Ratey 刚才提过他
Harvard Medical School professor,psychiatrist: "In a way,
哈佛医学院教授 精神病医生 "某种程度上
运动可以说是精神病医生的理想药物 exercise can be thought of as a psychiatrist’s dream treatment.
It works on anxiety,on panic disorder,and on stress in general,
它能对付焦虑症 恐慌症 普通的压力
which has a lot to do with depression.
压力和抑郁症有莫大关联
And it generates the release of neurotransmitters-
运动能释放神经递质
norepinephrine,serotonin,and dopamine-
去甲肾上腺素 血清素 多巴胺
that are very similar to our most important psychiatric medicines
这些物质与重要精神类药物相似
Having a bout of exercise is like taking a little bit of Prozac
做一轮运动就像吃了一点百忧解
and a little bit of Ritalin,right where it is supposed to go."
一点利他林 针对性很强"
The exact right amount of it.The exact right location.
正确的分量 正确的身体部位
And without side effects,
没有副作用
or with side effects- positive side effects,
也有副作用 积极的副作用
physical as well as mental and emotional side effects.
身体 精神 和情绪的副作用
What John Ratey is calling for in his wonderful,wonderful book-
John Ratey在他的一本很棒的书中呼吁
just came out recently in this January-
这本书今年一月份刚刚出版
what he calls for is an exercise revolution.
他呼吁发起运动革命
And he backs up this
对于这个呼吁
call with a lot of scientific evidence of why it is so important.
他用了大量科学证据来证明它的重要性
Let me show you just one area that he talks about.
我给大家讲他谈到的一个方面
He talks about all ages.
他谈到各种年龄层
He talks about kids,adults,as well as the elderly population.
孩子 成年人 还有老人
And it has positive effects for every age,from 0 to 120.
运动对每个年龄层都有积极作用 从0到120岁
Let me talk about a couple of studies and findings
我给大家讲几个研究和发现
that were implement-that exercise was implemented in schools.
这些研究是在学校推广运动
So there are a few schools that introduce physical exercise
有几间学校实行把运动
as an integral part of the curriculum.
作为一门必修课程
For example,and this is,has been replicated in a few schools-
例如 这个方法已经有几间学校效仿了
every morning,45 minutes of some form of exercise-
每天早上 做45分钟的运动
usually running,sometimes rowing,cycling,climbing.
通常是跑步 有时划船 骑自行车 爬山
There is a school in New Jersey
新泽西州有一间学校
that actually put a climbing wall where students exercised.
甚至在运动场安装了一面攀爬墙
But some form of the aerobic exercise,
一些有氧运动
sometimes intertwined with interval training.
有时换换花样 做间歇运动
Every morning,before school,45 minutes a day.
每天早上在上课前 45分钟运动
Some of the schools had it later during the day;
有些学校安排在上午以后
most of them in the mornings.
大部分学校安排在早上
Here are some of the results from some of the schools
这里就是其中一些学校得到的成效
that actually introduced it:
那些推行运动的学校
obesity levels,not surprising,went down.
肥胖水平下降 这是意料之内的
For example in Naperville in Illinois,in the district
例如在伊利诺斯州的Naperville区
there where physical exercise was introduced in school,-
那里的学校推广运动
which is by the way interesting because in most schools...
这种做法很有趣 因为大部分学校
Just yesterday I gave a talk at Horace Mann
昨天我在Horace Mann演讲
and the teachers told me that
那里的老师告诉我
in many of these schools in New York,
纽约很多学校
physical exercise has been taken out
都取消运动训练了
rather than more of it is introduces-
而不是提倡做更多运动
physical exercise and art both taken out.
运动训练和艺术课都取消了
Why? Because they have to get the grades- neck up.
为什么?为了考高分 专注于脖子以上
And that's a pity.And they pay a price.
这样很可悲 他们因此付出了代价
So obesity in a school in Naperville
Naperville的学校的肥胖水平下降
or in the district of Naperville in Illinois,
或者说伊利诺斯州的Naperville区
obesity levels went down
肥胖水平下降
from 30 percent to 3 percent among the students.
在学生中 从30%降到3%
That has repercussions not just for the students lives there-
这不仅对学生目前的生活有影响
that they are more comfortable,that they are happier;
他们身体更舒服了 心情更快乐了
it has repercussions and consequences for the rest of their lives.
对他们以后的生活也有影响
They are much less susceptible
他们不再那么易于
and prone to the chronic illnesses such as cancer,heart failure.
患上慢性疾病 例如癌症 心脏病
It's a win-win on so many level.
从很多方面来看都是双赢的
Much less susceptible to diabetics.
患糖尿病的可能性也降低了
So that's obesity.
这是肥胖症方面的效果
What they also find in Naperville is that
他们在Naperville区还发现了
the grades went up significantly.
分数大大的提高了
In fact,usually the US doesn't do very well,
其实美国学生通常
doesn't do very well when it comes to those international tests,
在国际测试中表现并不是很出色
maths and science tests that they do I think usually at 8th grade
八年级考的那些数学和科学考试
Well,Naperville is an exception.
但Naperville是一个例外
They scored No.16 in the world in mathematics
他们的数学成绩全世界排16名
and No.1 in the world in science.
科学成绩全世界排第一名
Now people argue that
有些人会反驳说
Naperville is an affluent neighborhood or district and it's true.
Naperville是一个富人区 确实如此
How about other places?
那其他地方呢?
Well they introduced exercise in very poor areas,in inner cities
一些很穷的内陆城市也推行了运动
For example,
例如
in Titusville,Pennsylvania,where many people are way below,
宾夕法尼亚州Titusville 很多人都低于
the average is way below the average income for the state.
平均工资远远低于这个州的平均工资
When before they introduced the exercise,school performance-
在推行运动之前 学校的教学成绩
they were significantly below state average,
远远低于州的平均水平
Pennsylvania's average.
宾夕法尼亚州的平均水平
After introducing exercise within a year,
推行运动一年后
they went up to 17 percent above state average.
成绩比州平均水平高17%
With the only change being there in that year-
当年学校唯一的变化
introducing physical exercise.
就是推行了运动训练
They've seen this in other schools in other districts as well.
其他地区的学校也发现同样现象
And what they also saw in the same school,
同时还发现在Titusville那所学校
in Titusville,that fist fights,for example they noticed,
他们发现 例如打架斗殴
violence disappeared completely as a result of the exercise,
因为推行运动训练 暴力完全消失
while they found also in a school in Iowa
而在爱荷华州一间学校也发现
where they introduced physical exercise,
在推行运动训练后
disciplinary problems went down from 225 to 95 in one year.
一年内纪律问题从225宗降到95宗
In another school in Kansas,also inner city,
在另一间堪萨斯州学校里 也是内陆城市
disciplinary problems went down by 67 percent
纪律问题下降了67%
after they introduced exercise.
这些都是在推行了运动训练以后
We are much less likely to be violent; it calms us;
暴力变少了 运动使我们平静
it brings us to our natural state of being,
使我们的身体处于自然状态
which is much calmer as opposed to being angry and upset.
这种状态更为平静 而不是苦闷愤怒
And people need to let out that steam.
人们需要释放那股怒气
Unfortunately very often
很不幸的是 通常
that steam is let out in fights with aggression.
人们都通过打架斗殴来释放
And this is a much healthier way to divert that healthy energy.
用运动将它转换成健康的活力更加有益身心
Let me show you a clip from one of my favorite movies,
我给大家看一段我最喜欢的一部电影
Legally Blonde.
《律政俏佳人》
And it's the part where
在这个镜头里
a woman is just being charged with the murder of her husband.And
一个女人刚刚被控谋杀亲夫
our very own law school graduate Reese Witherspoon defends her.
我们的法学院校友瑞茜・威瑟斯彭为她辩护
Whoops! Let me get to it.Thank you.
糟了 我找找看 谢谢
Videos.Legally...Here it is.
视频 律政 找到了
[VIDEO- Clip from "Legally Blonde"]
(律政俏佳人片段)
We're defending Brooke Windham,whose very wealthy husband
我们要为Brooke Windham辩护 她的有钱丈夫
was found shot to death in their Beacon Hill mansion.
被发现死在他们的Beacon Hill大宅里
Gold digger?
挖金女?
You'd think so since the stiff was sixty,
这样想也不奇怪 那老头都60了
but she was rich on her own.
但她自己也很有钱
Some kind of fitness empire.
拥有一间庞大的健身公司
You can buy her exercise tapes on infomercials.
电视导购节目上还卖她的健身录像
Are you talking about Brooke Taylor?
你说的人是Brooke Taylor?
Maiden name--Taylor.You know her?
娘姓是Taylor 你认识她?
She's a Delta Nu! She wasn't in my pledge class.
她是Delta Nu社团的 但她和我不是同期入会
She graduated four years before me.
她比我早四年毕业
But I used to take her class at the Los Angeles Sports Club.
我以前上过她在洛杉矶运动俱乐部的班
She's amazing!
她很厉害
Amazing? How?
怎么个厉害法?
She can make you lose three pounds in one class.
她可以帮你一节课减掉三磅
She's completely gifted.
她绝对是个天才
In all likelihood,she's completely guilty as well.
很可能她也绝对是个杀人犯
I just don't think Brooke could have done this.
我觉得Brooke不会杀人
Exercise gives you endorphins.
运动能产生内啡肽
Endorphins make you happy.
内啡肽能使人心情快乐
Happy people don't shoot their husbands.
快乐的人是不会杀自己丈夫的
They just don't.
绝对不会
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar: There you go.Sorry.
好了 对不起
You know in the book I talk about the happiness revolution.
大家知道在书里我谈过幸福革命
And I think based on a lot of research
根据很多研究
that the foundation for a happiness revolution
幸福革命的基础
has to come with an exercise revolution.
一定伴随着运动革命而来
Why? Because if we don't exercise,we are fighting against nature
为什么?因为如果我们不运动 就是违抗自然
So the foundation,the basis for the happiness revolution
所以幸福革命的基础
has to start neck down through the body.
必须始于脖子以下的身体
Let me move on to a second mind body intervention
我们接着讲第二个身心疗法
and that is meditation.
就是冥想
So what is meditation? I was first introduced to it through Yoga.
冥想是什么?我练瑜伽时第一次接触冥想
I got injured,playing squash,my back.
我当时打壁球弄伤了背
They told me Yoga would help.I started Yoga.
有人说练瑜伽有效果 我就开始练了
It helped my back and I got so much more out of it.
瑜伽不但治好了我的背 还有很多益处
In fact,so much more out of it that
太多益处了
I'm doing my teacher training now with Debbie Cohen,
所以我现在跟Debbie Cohen学当瑜伽老师
and will become a Yoga instructor,
将来会当上一名瑜伽老师
hopefully very soon if she passes me.
如果她让我通过 应该很快就能当了
There are other forms of mindful meditation- sitting meditation;
还有其他形式的意念冥想 静坐冥想
there is Tai Chi,Qi Gong;
太极 气功
there is meditation that just focuses on the breath;
还有把注意力放在呼吸上的冥想
there is meditation that focuses compassion.
有把注意力放在同情心上的冥想
There are a few common elements to most types of meditation.
这些冥想都有一个共同点
Let me mention a few of them.
我们来提其中几个
First of all,it's focusing on one thing,
首先 它们都专注于一件事物上
whether it's the movement,whether it's the posture,
可以是动作 姿势
whether it's the breath,
呼吸
whether it's compassion and loving and kindness,
同情心 爱 善心
whether it's a flame.
可以是火焰
Whatever it is,but it's focusing...
可以是…但它都专注于…
Whether it's a prayer.It's focusing on one thing.
可以是祈祷 反正就是一件事物上
Usually most forms of meditation-
通常大部分的冥想
the foundation is deep breathing.
基础都是深呼吸
In a sense the way a baby breathes.
就像婴儿呼吸一样
Belly breathing- breathe all the way to your belly
用腹部呼吸 把气一直吸进腹部
and then slowly,gently,gracefully breathing out.
然后慢慢地轻轻地呼出来
Deep breathing is usually the foundation-
深呼吸是很多冥想的基础
whether it's Tai Chi,Yoga,or sitting meditation.
不管是太极 瑜伽 还是静坐冥想
And finally,there is no good or bad meditation.
最后 冥想没有好坏之分
Meditation in a sense doesn't have a purpose
从某个方面讲 冥想没有目的
when you are meditating.
在你冥想时 没有目的
You are giving yourself the permission to be human.
你不能强求自己
There is no "ah I just had an amazing meditation,"
不会说"我刚刚做了一次很棒的冥想"
or "I just feel enlightened."
或者"我觉悟了"
In fact,let me tell you a story about
其实 我来给大家讲一个故事
how I became enlightened through meditation.
关于我是如何通过冥想觉悟的
So last year,I used to travel quite a bit.
去年 我以前经常出行
We lived in Israel,
我们那时住在以色列
but I travelled once a month on average to the US for a few days.
我平均每个月来美国几天
And when I travelled here,
当我来到这里时
I used to give talks but also used that time as a form of retreat
我通常都是演讲 还会借机静修
And what I would do was I practiced a lot of Yoga,
我会做很多瑜伽
much more than I did in Israel.
比我在以色列做得要多
I did a lot of meditation.I had a lot of time between talks.
我做很多冥想 两场演讲之间有很多闲余时间
So plenty of time I used it as a retreat.
我经常利用这些时间静修
And I remember one time coming home back to Israel and-
我记得有一次回到以色列
I just give you the context.
我给大家讲一下当时的情景
In Israel,we live in a city just outside Tel Aviv,
在以色列 我们住在特拉维夫外的一个城市
called Ramat Gan.
叫Ramat Gan
And we live- our house is in a 20-story building-
我们的房子在一栋20层的建筑里
we live on the 10th floor.
我们住在10楼
And the view is just breath-taking.
景色美不胜收
You know Israel is just a very tiny country,so you can see...
以色列是一个很小的国家
I can see both sides of Israel- the Mediterranean on one side;
我可以看到以色列的两边 一边是地中海
I can see the Mountains of Samir on the other side.
另一边能看到萨米尔山区
Just gorgeous view.
非常美丽的景色
And one of the things that I like to do is every morning-
我喜欢每天早上…
because I'm a morning person-
因为我是一个早起的人
I wake up usually before the rest of the family.
通常比家人起得都要早
I sit down in the dining room
我在客厅坐下
and look outside through the glass window.
透过玻璃窗看外面
We have a glass window.
我们有一个玻璃窗
Since it's so high,
因为楼层很高
it's fortified glass of course and part of it does not open.
我们用的是强化玻璃 有些窗是开不了的
But I look through the part that does not open outside.
我透过那扇没打开的窗看外面
And I do it very often.
我经常这样看
And I remember coming back from this particular trip and,
我记得有一次从美国回来后
from the US,and looking outside and suddenly,
我看窗外 突然
all the colors seem so much brighter.
所有颜色都变得鲜艳多了
The world seems so much clear.
整个世界似乎都变得更明亮了
And I say to myself,"wow.I must've become enlightened."
我心里想"我肯定觉悟了"
Because I read in books and I heard people talking about it
因为我在书上看过有人说
that when you become enlightened,everything becomes clear.
当你觉悟时 一切事物都变得明亮
The world becomes even more beautiful than it already is.
世界变得比原来更美了
And I were sitting there on the sofa,
我坐在沙发上
and just admiring the strong colors,
欣赏着鲜艳的颜色
the beauty,the clarity of every thing.
美景 明亮的世界
And I said to myself,"after so many years"-
我心想"经过这么多年"
I've been meditating for over ten years,
我冥想了十年了
"after so many years,I'm finally enlightened."
"经过这么多年 我终于觉悟了"
And I started to act differently,
我的行为举止开始变了
because you know enlightened people
因为觉悟了的人
don't go around telling people they are enlightened.
不会到处告诉别人他们觉悟了
Well,this is an exception.
这节课是一个例外
But...So I didn't tell anyone.
但…我没有告诉别人
I didn't even tell Tammy that I'm enlightened.
我甚至没有告诉Tammy我觉悟了
But I was walking on air and the next day,the next morning,
第二天早上 我步履轻盈了
I would wake up and again my ritual observation on off
我醒来又开始我每天例行的看景
the mountains in a distance and I said,
看着远处的山 我想
"wow.The world is so beautiful.I'm enlightened."
"世界太美丽了 我觉悟了"
And that went on for a few days.
这种情况持续了几天
Then one day,Tammy and I were sitting together in the lounge,
有一天 Tammy和我坐在休息室里
and just chatting.
我们在聊天
And you know she was looking outside and I was looking outside.
她看着窗外 我也看窗外
And she said,"you know finally when you went away,
她说"你去了美国的这段时间
after so long,I finally was able to clean the window."[Laugh]
我终于能把窗户擦干净了"
I said,I said,"what?"
我说"什么?"
And she said,"you know I haven't been able to get out there.
她说"我一直都够不着窗外
But I got this machine.
但我买了一个机器
You know the two side machine with a,with a magnet.
一个有两边的机器 有一块磁铁的
I was finally able to get it.And I finally cleaned the window."
我终于买到这个机器 把窗擦干净了"
So much for my enlightenment.
我的觉悟原来是一场空欢喜
So you know,maybe there is enlightenment- I don't know.
也许真的有觉悟这回事 我也不知道
But the key with meditation is not about reaching that stage,
但冥想的关键并不是达到这种境界
when everything suddenly becomes so clear.
看到一切都变明亮了
You know I think the quicker path would be to clean the window.
要想这样 把窗户擦干净可能更快
But that's not what meditation is about.
但觉悟不是冥想的目的
Meditation is about being present,being in the here and now,
冥想是专注于现状 此时此刻
struggling with being in the here and now.
与此时此刻的存在作挣扎
And when we lose our thought,
当我们思想涣散了
when we lose our focus on the breath,simply bring it back.
当我们对呼吸分心了 集中回来就行了
That is the practice- losing it and bringing it back.
这就是冥想 分心 集中
Losing it and bringing it back.
分心 集中
And that's how we exercise our mind to be more focused,
这样我们就能把思想锻炼得更专注
to be more mindful.
更留神
So let me share with you some of the studies on meditation.
我给大家讲几个对冥想的研究
And once you start meditation or Yoga by the way,
对了 一旦你开始做冥想或瑜伽
you will find what is right for you.
你会摸索出适合自己的方式
Being ADHD,it was very difficult for me to do sitting meditation
我有多动症 很难静下来坐着冥想
Much more conducive for me to do Yoga.
做瑜伽对我更有用
Because I'm working hard.
因为我练瑜伽时很认真
It keeps my mind focused on the posture.
瑜伽能把我的注意力集中在姿势上
For other people,the right thing is sitting meditation.
对其他人来说 静坐冥想更适合
Just breathing.
静坐呼吸
For others,it's thinking about certain things.
有些人会想着某一件事物
For many people,it's praying.
很多人会祈祷
Whatever works for you.
只要适合你就行了
And it can be of course a few things.
你甚至可以同时做几件事
You can pray and do Yoga.
你可以一边祈祷一边做瑜伽
So let me share with you some of the studies.
我来给大家讲几个研究
The real serious studies on meditation
关于冥想的严肃研究
started by looking at the tip of the stem.
一开始是研究冥想界中的佼佼者
The meditators,people who have been doing it for many years,
那些练习冥想很多年的冥想者
for a very long time.
练习了很久的人
And what they asked,the researchers like Richie Davidson,
这些研究者包括Richie Davidson
University of Wisconsin,
任职于威斯康星大学
Jon Kabat-Zinn from University of Worcester,
伍斯特大学的Jon Kabat-Zinn
people like Herbert Benson,
像Herbert Benson这样的人
Paul Ackerman from one the UCs,and other people.
加州大学的Paul Ackerman 还有其他人
When they wanted to study meditation,
他们想研究冥想时
they said "let's study the best."
他们说"我们来研究最好的冥想者"
So they contacted the Dalai Lama himself and said,
所以他们联系了达赖喇嘛 说
"can you suggest some people who have been meditating
"你能推荐一些冥想了
for a very long time- serious meditators;
很久的认真的冥想者吗
and we want to study their brain."
我们想研究他们的大脑"
So they did.And they brought them in.
他们找到了 把这些人找来
And what they looked for,the first thing,remember,
他们研究的第一样东西是 大家应该记得
left to right prefrontal cortex ratio.
左前额皮层和右前额皮层的比例
And if you remember,we talked about it-
大家记得 我们之前谈过
people who are happier generally have more activation
快乐的人通常更活跃的地方
on the left side of the prefrontal cortex;
是左前额皮层
people who are less happy have more activation
不快乐的人更活跃的地方
on the right side of the prefrontal cortex.
是右前额皮层
So that ratio is important.
所以这个比例很重要
And it's one of the "objective" means of measuring happiness.
它是测量快乐的一个"客观"手段
One of the things that they have found is that
他们得出的一个发现是
there is very high correlation
两者之间存在很大关联
between what our brains look like under the scanner
在扫描器下看到的大脑
and our self-report about how happy we are-
和我们对自己是否快乐的自我报告
not 100 percent correlation,not at 1,but pretty high,
当然不是100%的关联 但也不低 很高
suggesting the self-reports are pretty,are quite reliable.
这表明自我报告是很可靠的
But anyway,so they wanted to look at the brain of the meditators
总之 他们想研究这些冥想者的大脑
And when they looked at the general public,
他们再比较普通大众
we all exist on a Bell curve.
我们都在一个钟形曲线内
The happier people are further on
快乐的人更靠前
more activation on the left side;
左侧皮层更活跃
the less happy people are further-
不快乐的人更靠后
more activation,higher ratio on the right side.
右侧皮层更活跃
And then they brought in the meditators.
然后他们找来这些冥想者
And they measured their left to right prefrontal cortex.
测出他们左前额皮层和左前额皮层的比例
And here is what they found.
这是他们的研究发现
This is the normal Bell curve.
这是正常的钟形曲线
This is where the meditators were.
冥想者在这里
This is from 2001- since,they have found numerous meditators
这是2001年的研究 他们找了很多冥想者
that are quite literally off the chart,
他们几乎偏离了这个图
suggesting very high levels of well being and happiness.
表明快乐的程度很高
Being susceptible to positive emotions,
他们很容易感染积极情绪
and resilient in the face of painful emotions.
对痛苦情绪的抵抗力很强
So this is a remarkable result.
这是一个很惊人的结果
Again,results that are not seen before
这些结果之前没人发现过
until they measured these meditators.
直到他们研究了这些冥想者
The other things that
另一个研究方面就是
they were interested is looking at other important indicator
他们想看看另一个重要的指标
for well being and calmness is the startle response.
衡量健康和冷静的惊吓反应
When you hear a bang,you startle.
当你听到一声巨响 你会吓一跳
And the startle response is important,
这个惊吓反应很重要
because the easier you get startled,
因为你越容易受到惊吓
generally it's correlated to the higher levels of anxiety,
通常说明你焦虑程度更高
susceptibility at least to anxiety.
至少容易产生焦虑
And everyone has this startle response to some degree.
大家都有一定的惊吓反应
Even marksmen and women in the military,
即使是军队里的神枪手
you know,who shoot their guns everyday
他们每天都射枪
and they are trying to remain completely focus.
他们要完全集中注意力
Even they startle,when the gun goes off.
当枪走火时 他们也会受到惊吓
They flinch.Very slightly,but they do.
他们会微微地抖一下 这也是惊吓反应
So it's impossible to suppress the startle response.
要压抑惊吓反应是不可能的
Or so they thought.
或者说当时的人是这样想的
When Paul Ackerman brought these meditators in
Paul Ackerman找来这些冥想者
and asked them to maintain complete equanimity and calmness,
叫他们保持绝对镇定和冷静
and he startled them.
他吓他们
There was no reaction whatsoever.First time in recorded history.
他们一点反应都没有 有记录以来第一次
That people are,have been able to suppress the startle response.
有人能够抑压自己的惊吓反应
Here was what Daniel Goleman writes about this in his book,
Goleman writes在他的书中这样写道
Destructive Emotions: "Given that the larger someone's startle,
破坏性情绪 "一个人惊吓反应越大
the more intensely that
那个人就越可能
person tends to experience upsetting emotions,
出现消极情绪
Oser's performance had tantalizing implications,
Oser的表现有着有趣的含意
suggesting a remarkable level of emotional equanimity."
表明他的情绪有着惊人的镇定"
That equanimity was also contagious-
这种镇定还会传染
so people who tried to argue with these monks,
如果有人想和这些喇嘛争吵
very often had a hard time becoming angry or upset
他们会很难生起气来
even if the topic was upset,personally upsetting to them,
即使这个话题很容易让他们生气
such as scientists arguing about the existence of God.
例如科学家争论上帝是否存在
And they said,"I couldn't get upset."
他们说"我生不起气来"
Because calm is contagious,just like happiness is.
因为平静是会传染的 就是快乐会传染一样
Now some of you may not be 100 percent clear about
有些同学可能不百分百了解
what the startle response is.
什么是惊吓反应
So for those of you who are not,I've prepared a very brief clip.
对于不了解惊吓反应的同学 我准备了一个短片
[VIDEO: Clip on Startle Response]
(惊吓反应视频)
Oh sure the mask doesn't do anything to him.
面具吓不了他
But you wanna see something really scary?
你想知道什么吓到他了吗?
It's Dad![Laugh]
是爸爸
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar: OK.All right.Now you understand.
好了 现在大家明白了
When they studied these meditators,
他们研究这些冥想者时
essentially what they were doing was applying
基本上他们方法就是应用
what we've talked about,
我们之前讲过的
the growing tip statistic or Maslow talks about,
生长锥数据 或者Maslow讲过的
the growing tip statistic- studying the best.
生长锥数据 研究最好的
Because if you want to advance knowledge,
因为如果你想推动知识发展
if you want to better apply ideas that work,
如果你想更好地应用可行理论
you don't study the average teacher,you study Marva Colins.
你不会研究普通老师 你会研究Marva Colins
You don't study the average meditator,
你不会研究普通的冥想者
who thinks he's enlightened,you study the meditators
自以为觉悟了的冥想者 你研究那些
who have been doing it for for many years.
冥想了很多年的冥想者
Lama Oser,one of these meditators:
其中一个冥想者Oser喇嘛说
"The process itself has some extraordinary qualities,
"冥想本身有一些与众不同的特质
but not necessarily the subject.
但这与进行冥想的人无关
The important idea is that this process is within the reach of
重要的一点是 冥想并非触不可及的
anyone who applies himself or herself with enough determination."
只要你有足够的决心来练习它"
In other words,this is not just for the selected few,
也就是说 冥想并不专属于少数几个人
who can meditate for 30 years,8 hours a day.
那些每天8小时地冥想了30年的人
It can be applied
大家都可以冥想
because the process is relatively simple to all of us.
因为这个过程对所有人来说都很简单
Daniel Goleman: "From the perspective of neuroscience,
Daniel Goleman说"从神经科学的角度看
the point of all this research
这个研究的重点
has nothing to do with demonstrating that
并不是为了说明
Oser or any other extraordinary person
Oser或者其他厉害的冥想者
may be remarkable in him-or herself,but
本身有什么过人之处
rather to stretch the field's assumptions about human possibility
而是为了扩展这个领域对于人体潜力的假设
Some of these key assumptions have already begun to expand,
其中一些关键假设已经开始扩展了
in part due to a revolution in neuroscience's supposition
部分原因是神经科学
about the malleability of the brain itself."
对大脑可塑性作出革命性猜想"
Remember neuroplasticity.Neurogenesis.
大家记住 神经塑性 神经形成
These concepts that I and...
这些概念 我和
how scientists like Richie Davidson identified
像Richie Davidson这样的科学家认为
that our brain is malleable,it can change.
大脑是可塑的 可以改变的
And one of the ways to change it is through meditation.
改变的方法之一就是冥想
Now this is all well and good.
这种观点非常好
So we can apply this process with determination to our lives.
所以我们可以下决心把它应用于生活中
But how many people here seriously would say,
但这课室里有多少人会认真地说
"OK.That sounds great.
"听起来很好
I want my left side of the prefrontal cortex to be more active.
我想我的左前额皮层更活跃
So I'm gonna go off to Himalayas
所以我要去喜马拉雅山
and meditate for 30 years,8 hours a day.
每天8小时地冥想30年"
I mean,how many people are really prepared to do this?
有多少人真的准备这么做?
How many people have time for 2 hours a day of meditation?
有多少人每天有两小时做冥想?
The second problem with this research is that it's correlational.
这个研究的第二个问题是 两者之间只是关联
There's no causation here.
但并没有因果关系
Maybe Lama Oser was born that way;
也许Oser喇嘛天生就是这样
that's why he was attracted to meditation.
所以他才对冥想产生兴趣
Maybe Matthieu Ricard- he's written a book on happiness-
也许Matthieu Ricard…他写了一本关于幸福的书
Dalai Lama's translator,right-hand man.
他是达赖喇嘛的翻译 一个右撇子
Maybe he was born that way
也许他天生就是这样
with a remarkable left to right prefrontal cortex.
左前额皮层比右前额皮层活跃得多
He's,by the way,literally off the charts.
对了 他的比例完全超出钟形曲线
But the main problem still remains- beyond causation is the time.
除了因果关系 还有一个主要问题 时间
Do we have the time,
我们有时间吗
do we have the patience to meditate so often and so much?
我们有耐心经常长时间冥想吗?
You know when I found out,when I started to meditate,
我发现当我开始冥想
to do Yoga,I really saw the benefits of it.
开始做瑜伽时 我真的能看到益处
And I said,"OK.So I'm getting the benefits
我说"我每天做半小时
when I am doing it for half an hour a day.
就能收到成效了
What if I do a real,longer retreat?"
如果我进行一次长时间静修呢?"
And I have some great 10 day long retreats.
所以我想进行十天的静修
And I said to Tammy,
我跟Tammy
"you know,I want to go to a 10 day retreat."
"我想去静修十天"
And Tammy knows me pretty well,
Tammy很了解我
and she said,"you know,why don't you try...
她说"不如你试试…
You know it's not all or nothing.
你不用要么不做 要么就做到足
Why don't you try a one day retreat first
不如你试试先静修一天
before you go on a 10 day retreat?"
然后再进行为期十天的静修?"
And I said,"you know,it's a good idea!"
我说"这是个好主意"
And I went to a one day retreat,
我开始为期一天的静修
which is not very far from here,in Cambridge.
离这里不远 就在剑桥
And I went to this retreat and I was very excited.
我踏上这段静修之行 非常激动
It was on a Saturday.And I was looking for it all week.
那天是星期六 我盼了一整周
I said,"I'm starting the process of enlightenment,
我当时想"通过这一天的静修
of course,through this one day retreat.
我就踏上觉悟之路了
And once after that one day retreat,
等我做完这一天的静修
once I prove to Tammy that it's good for me,
等我向Tammy证明这对我有很大益处时
she'll see how calm I am after.
她就会看到我静修后有多平静
She'll say,'sure.Go for the 10 day retreat."
她就会说'好的 去静修十天吧'"
So I went for that one day retreat.
所以我去了静修一天
And the one day retreat- we came in; there was a gentleman
那一天的静修 我们进去看到一个男人
who was sitting in front of the class with the beard,
长着胡子 坐在一班学生前
looking very calm.
显得非常平静
And I said,"I'm going to look like him at the end of the day.
我想"静修完今天 我就能像他那样了
And...Minus the beard." And we sat down.
除了没他的胡子" 我们坐下
He said,"we are going to start with sitting meditation."
他说"我们先从静坐冥想开始"
So we all sat.
我们都坐下
You know we had our cushion.I need a few cushions there.
我们都有坐垫 我需要几个坐垫
We were sitting there.I put my hands here.
我们坐在那里 我把手放在这里
He said,"OK.Breathe deeply.Through your nostrils.
他说"好了 深呼吸 从鼻孔吸进去
And then breathe out again."
然后呼出来"
And we did that.And I was sitting there.
我们跟着做 我坐在那里
And my mind- you know being ADHD- started to wander.
我有多运症 我的思想开始涣散
But he said,"if the mind wanders,bring it back to the focus."
他说"如果思想涣散了 集中回来"
And we were sitting there and for-
我们坐了…
what it seems like- a very long time.
我觉得很长时间
And I stayed there.And I said,"OK.Your mind wanders.It's OK.
我坚持住 我想"你思想涣散了 没关系
Come back to it." And I continued to sit there.
集中回来" 我继续坐在那里
And we sat there for 45 minutes.And at the end,he said,
我们坐了45分钟 最后他说
"OK.Gently,slowly open your eyes.And stand up."
"慢慢地轻轻地睁开眼睛 站起来"
And he said,"what we are gonna do now,
他说"接下来
the second part after the 45 minutes,
经过45分钟后 我们开始第二部分
first part,the sitting meditation-
第一部分是静坐冥想
we are going to do some walking meditation."
接下来我们要行走冥想"
And he illustrated it.
他解释了一下
And then we walked behind him,around in a circle.
然后我们围成一个圈 跟着他走
And we walked very slowly,very diligently.
我们走得很慢 很认真
Just focusing on each step.Lifting up the leg.
把注意力集中到每一步上 把腿抬起
He said,"just focus on the movement.
他说"集中到动作上
Be present in the here and now.And if your mind wanders,"
专注于此时此刻 如果你思想涣散了"
which mine did constantly,"bring it back to the walking.
我经常这样 "再集中回行走上
And continue to breathe deeply.
继续深呼吸
Just like what you did in the sitting meditation."
就像刚才静坐冥想一样"
So we were walking around the room for a very long time.
所以我们绕着房间 走了很久
And we walked.And we continued to walk around that room.
继续走 绕着房间走
And my mind continued to wander.And I got bored.
我的思想继续涣散 我感到无聊了
So what I did was I started to look around at the other people.
我开始四处看别人
And they were all walking in the circle.
他们都绕着圈子走着
And then I looked to where the teacher was sitting.
然后我看了老师坐的地方
And next to the teacher,there was a piece of paper.
老师旁边有一张纸
I thought,"oh interesting.I wonder what it says there."
我想"真有趣 不知道上面写了什么呢"
So I continued to walk and I got to the piece of paper again.
所以我继续走 又走到那张纸那里
And I said,"oh it's a schedule.How interesting!"
我想"是时间安排表 真有趣"
And I didn't have enough time to read what it said.
我不够时间看清上面写什么
So I said,"next round I have something to look forward to!"
我想"下一圈我就有盼头了"
So I continued to walk.And I see...
所以我继续走 我看到…
Oh I see this is what we did- 45 minutes of sitting meditation
我看到我们刚上完的课 45分钟静坐冥想
and after that 45 minutes of walking meditation.Ha?
后面就是45分钟的行走冥想
I wonder what's next.And I continued to walk.
接下来是什么呢?我继续走
And now I have something to look forward to.I was excited.
我有盼头了 所以很高兴
And I look just below- 45 minutes of sitting meditation?
我往下看 45分钟静坐冥想?
And then- 45 minutes of walking meditation?
然后 45分钟行走冥想?
Wow! And another sitting and walking...
又是静坐和行走
Oh and lunch! I wonder what we do after lunch!
然后是午餐 午餐后面是什么呢?
45 minutes of sitting meditation? And walking...Wow.
45分钟静坐冥想?然后是行走…天啊
And after that,walking meditation? So I thought to myself,
然后是行走冥想?于是我心里想
"wow.This is incredible! I'll see you next time! Jeez!"
"太恐怖了 再见 天啊"
And I walked out.I just...I couldn't take it! So...
我走出去了 我受不了了 所以…
And I ran home,but I must say,I was a little bit embarrassed.
我跑回家了 说实话我感到很尴尬
So I said,"wait.Maybe I'll spend the day outside."
所以我想"不如我在外面逛一天"
You know,just come back home and seem enlightened at least.
回家时装出一副觉悟的样子
But I didn't.So I called Tammy.
但我没有这样做 我打给Tammy
And I told her,"do you want to have breakfast together?"
我告诉她"你想和我一起吃早餐吗?"
And we did.She gives me the permission to be human.
我们一起吃了 她明白这是人之常情
I don't see myself going on a 10 day retreat.
我觉得自己无法静修十天
I don't see myself going on a 30 year retreat.
我觉得自己无法静修30年
And my question was that as it is now,
我的问题是 在这种情况下
how can meditation help people who don't want to
那些不想 或者无法长时间冥想的人
or simply can't meditate for such a long time?
冥想怎么帮得了他们?
And don't get me wrong.
别误会我的意思
I do recommend these retreats.
我推荐大家进行静修
There are people who go to these retreats
有些人去了静修以后
and come out looking differently.
变得不同了
I mean I've seen...I know.Many of my friends have been there.
我见过 我有很多朋友去过
But that's- again,a one day retreat or a 10 day retreat;
再说回来 静修一天还是十天…
some people have gone as long to as 3 months retreat
有些人静修了长达三个月
and they are good.
他们都取得很好成果
Just not for me.
但我坚持不来
So what can we do? Jon Kabat-Zinn in his research,
我们该怎么做呢?Jon Kabat-Zinn在他的研究中
showed how meditation can apply to people
告诉了我们冥想如何应用于
who don't want to do full days,who just have 45 minutes a day
那些没有一整天闲余时间 每天只能抽45分钟的人
or as little as 15 minutes a day for meditation or Yoga,
甚至如何每天抽15分钟冥想或者做瑜伽
or some form of mindfulness.
或者其他形式的意念练习
And he did two things.
他做了两件事
First of all,
第一件
he showed how it helps for people who do less than 30 years.
他表明了冥想不到30年的人从中得到什么益处
And second,equally important,he showed causation.
第二件同样重要 他表明了因果关系的存在
So he took two groups in one of his studies.
他的一个研究中有两组人
Two groups.
两组
The one group- both groups wanted to do meditation,
两组都想做冥想
so they expressed the interest-
他们都有这个兴趣
one group he put on a waiting list.
他让其中一组等候
And he said,
他说
you are participating this seminar in about three months.
你们将在三个月后参加这个冥想班
Or...It was 4 months.In 4 months,
是四个月 四个月后
you'll be participating the seminar where all booked out.
你们将参加这个报满了的冥想班
The second group started the meditation regime workshop then.
第二组开始这个班的冥想练习
And the regime was essentially 45 minutes of meditation a day.
他们的练习就是每天冥想45分钟
During the weekend,they were together;
周末时他们会聚到一起
they learned some techniques.
学习一些技巧
But during the week,when they were at home,
但在工作日时 他们在家里
45 minutes a day of meditation.
每天冥想45分钟
And then he compared them to the control group-
然后他拿他们跟参考组对比
the group that was waiting for a retreat,waiting for the lessons
参考组就是那个等待参加冥想班的组
Because he wanted them to be the same kind-
因为他希望实验对象都是
people who wanted to do meditation.
想做冥想的人
One that has actually started; one that is going to start soon.
一组已经开始冥想 另一组迟点再开始
And then he measured anxiety and compared to the control group-
然后他测量焦虑程度 对比参考组
anxiety levels of those who did meditation for 8 weeks.
那个冥想了八周的人的焦虑程度
Just 8 weeks.45 minutes a day on average.
平均每天45分钟 只做了八周
Anxiety decreased significantly.
焦虑程度大大降低
Then he looked at their happiness level,
然后他研究他们的快乐程度
like the positive- not just the negative to the zero;
积极的情绪 他不只关注消极程绪
the zero to the positive.
从消极到积极的都关注
And they were happier.They had better moods.
他们更快乐了 心情更好了
After as little as 8 weeks.But here are the clinchers.
仅仅八周 但关键还在后头
He then said,
他说
"well,it's not enough- just self-reported could be placebo,"-
"这还不够 自我报告有可能产生安慰剂效应"
which is great,
这个想法很好
but he wanted to see something else beyond just placebo.
他要不受安慰剂效应影响的证据
And here is what he found.
然后他有了这个发现
He looked at their left to right prefrontal cortex.
他研究他们的左右前额皮层比例
And after as little as 8 weeks,
仅仅八周之后
there was a significant difference
那些冥想的人
in those individuals who meditated.
就出现显著的变化
Now this is a remarkable result.
这是一个很惊人的结果
Remember until 1998,
大家记住 1998年之前
scientists were sure that the brain is not malleable;
科学家都深信大脑是不可塑的
does not change pass the age of 3 or so.
过了三岁以后就不会改变
And suddenly here with this little,with as little as 8 weeks,
突然仅仅八周的练习
these meditators,or individuals,
这些冥想的人
you know regular people doing 45 minutes of meditation a day,
每天有规律地冥想45分钟的人
are changing the way their brain functions,
改变了他们大脑的机能
making them more susceptible to positive emotions,
使得他们更容易感染积极情绪
more resilient in the face of painful emotions.
对痛苦情绪的抵抗力更强
Herbert Benson from our medical school here
我们哈佛医学院的Herbert Benson
are showing with as little as 15-20 minutes a day of meditation,
发现每天做15到20分钟的冥想
you see a significant change over time in levels of well being.
做了一段时间后 就能大大地改善健康
Emotional well being as well as physical well being.
情绪健康和身体健康都改善了
Because the other study that Jon Kabat-Zinn did
因为Jon Kabat-Zinn做了另一个研究
with these meditators was injecting both groups-
他给两组人都注射了…
the control group who are waiting and the meditators.
那组等候冥想的参考组和进行冥想的那组
He injected them with cold bacteria.
他给他们注射了感冒细菌
And what he wanted to do,what he wanted to measure was
他想测的是
how would their bodies react in terms of antibodies.
他们体内的抗体会有什么反应
And what he found was that the meditators' immune response
他发现冥想者的免疫反应
was significantly stronger than those who didn't meditate,
比那些没有冥想的人强了很多
who were waiting to meditate.
那些在等候冥想的人
Just based on 8 weeks of meditation,45 minutes a day.
只需八周的冥想 每天45分钟
And we know that.
我们知道
You know when we are calmer,
你们知道当我们更平静时
we are less susceptible to illnesses.
我们对疾病的抵抗力就会增强
When we are stressed,we are more susceptible to illnesses.
我们焦虑时 就更容易患上疾病
So meditation strengthens both-
所以冥想能加强
the psychological immune system in making us more resilient,
心理免疫系统 增强心理抵抗力
as well as the physical immune system.
同时还能改善身体免疫系统
Mindfulness has been used in numerous areas,
意志训练应用于很多领域
numerous places as therapy.
成为很多领域中的一种治疗方法
More and more so today.
今天就更是如此了
Both as in,together with cognitive therapy,
配合认知疗法
together with medicine,medication as well as on its own.
配合药物 冥想 或者单纯冥想
And it's been shown to be extremely effective.
研究已经表明这种方法非常有效
The book I recommend,
我推荐一本书
if you want to get a good outline of what the field has to say
如果你想对这个领域有一个深刻的初步认识
is called The Mindful Way Through Depression.
我推荐大家看《改善情绪的正念疗法》
It talks about
这本书是讲
how mindfulness can help us overcome major depression,
意念如何能帮我们克服严重抑郁
mild depression as well as things like anxiety
中度抑郁 或者焦虑
and how it can also help other psychological disorders.
还能改善其他心理疾病
And one of the things for example that they show there-
例如这本书中讲到的一件事
we know from,
我们知道
unfortunately we know that once someone has major depression,
很不幸 一旦一个人患了严重抑郁
the likelihood of it reappearing,
复发的可能
whether it's a month later or sometimes years later
不管是一周后 还是一年后
is much higher than if we never have major depression.
比从来没患过严重抑郁的人要高很多
Why? Think about what we have discussed before.
为什么?回忆一下我们之前讲过的内容
What we talked about is how the brain creates neural pathways.
我们讲过大脑是如何形成神经通路的
Now if a neural pathway has been created-
一旦神经通路形成
and it's a strong neural pathway of depression,
因为抑郁症的神经通路很强烈
very often something which is relatively mild
通常一点相对不严重的事发生了
but happens can send us back to that neural pathway.
都能让这条神经通路活跃过来
So we through a relatively hard period,nothing that serious,but
如果我们有一段时间情绪不好 哪怕是一点小事
immediately the brain looks for that the largest neural pathway,
马上大脑就会寻找最大的那条神经通路
the largest river metaphorically speaking.
形象一点说 最大的那条河流
And it goes there.
它就会找到那条通路
And we have the major depression again with little reason.
所以因为一点很小的原因 严重抑郁症复发了
And after we have it two or three times,
复发了两三次后
the neural pathway is even stronger,even more likely to recur.
这条神经通道更强烈了 复发可能性更高了
What he found when they introduced mindfulness meditation or
他发现 当他们进行正念冥想
mindfulness therapy in addition to cognitive behavioral therapy
或者正念疗法 再配以认知行为疗法
was it reduced the likelihood of recurrence of major depression
就能减少严重抑郁症复发的可能
among people who have major depression or had major depression-
那些患有 或曾经患过严重抑郁症的人
reduces the likelihood by over 50 percent of relapse.
能减少50%的复发可能
That is a longitudinal study.So that really helps.
这是一个纵向研究 这种方法真的很有用
It also helps deal with non major depression.
还能改善中度以下的的抑郁症
It helps dealing with sadness.
帮助处理悲伤情绪
Now how does it work? How does it work?
这种方法是怎么起作用的?
Let me very briefly- again I do recommend this book;
我简单地…再说一次 我很推荐这本书
we can have a whole course on this book.
光用这本书就可以开一门课程
This book also got an 8 week program which is fantastic.
这本书还介绍了一个很棒的八周疗法
Its first level is about awareness
第一步是察觉
and acceptance of the body signal.
并接受身体信号
What do they mean here?
这是什么意思?
You see,whenever we enter experiencing emotion,
当我们感受到一种情绪时
there is always a physical manifestation to it.
通常会伴有一个身体反应
Positive emotions such as happiness- it could be butterflies or
例如像快乐这样的积极情绪 可能会忐忑
you know just feeling very broad in the upper body whatever it is
可能只是会感到上半身豁然开朗
but also painful emotions.
痛苦情绪也有身体反应
For example,
例如
if I experience,personal when I experience anxiety,it's here.
我个人来说 当我感到焦虑时 这里
I feel it here.
我能感受到它在这里
Or here.The knot in my stomach that I talked about.
或者这里 我以前讲过 就像胃打了个结一样
People who experience depression or even sadness,
感受到抑郁甚至悲伤的人
feel it somewhere- again whether it's in the stomach,
会感觉到它在某一身体部位 可能在胃
whether it's in the shoulders,
可能在肩膀
there is always a physical manifestation
一个情绪
to an emotional experience.
总是伴有身体反应的
And what they are saying and what the research has shown
研究者认为 以及研究发现表明
is that when we begin to experience a painful emotion,
当我们开始感受到痛苦情绪时
immediately going and becoming mindful,
我们马上就要开始运用意念
aware of where the physical manifestation is.
开始找出这个身体反应在哪里
So instead of beginning to ruminate
而不要钻角头尖
and to dwell on "why am I depressed","what's going on",
"为什么我会抑郁""怎么回事"
"what's happening","not again","I hope this won't start..."
"发生什么事了""又犯了""千万别又犯了"
Instead of going in to this rumination,
我们不要马上想到这些
going immediately to the physical manifestation of it,
而是马上找出这个情绪的身体反应
to the body.
想到身体
So I'm beginning to feel stressed.OK.
我开始感到有压力 好的
And focusing on it and accepting that knot.
把注意力集中到这里 接受这个结
Not trying to fix it as we'll talk about in a minute.
不要尝试去消除它 这点我们稍后会谈
Simply accepting it for what it is,looking at it and saying,
只需接受它的存在 看着它想
"oh.That's interesting.Oh it's quite a big knot.
"真有趣 很大的一个结"
Oh no it's small.Oh it's getting actually bigger."
"不 很小 在变大了"
As opposed to saying
而不要想
"I want it to go away.Oh it is going away.That's interesting."
"我想它消失 它消失了 真有趣"
But that's not the purpose.
这不是这一步的目的
The purpose is simply to become aware of it,
这一步的目的只需察觉到它的存在
simply to become aware of
只需察觉到
whatever the physical manifestation of the emotion is.
这种情绪引起的身体反应
Now why does it work?
为什么这样能行得通?
It works because it creates an alternative neural pathway.
它能行得通是因为它形成了一条新的神经通路
With a usual pathway that it's created,when we feel dis-easy,
在原来的神经通路下 当我们感到不适时
it's going into the mind,ruminating about it
脑袋就会发现不适 苦苦思索它
and usually going to the channel that existed before.
通常就会走回原有的通路里
The channels or channels that existed before,
这些原来的通路
and these channels are associated with our depression
是和我们的抑郁相连的
or previous negative experiences that have been reinforced.
和我们之前的消极情绪相连 并且得到增强
What we are doing now,
我们现在要做的
instead of going into these enforced channels inside our mind
不是走回我们脑袋里这些增强了的通路上
and further reinforcing them,
并且再一次增强它们
we are creating an alternative one- oh pain?!
而是形成一条新的通路 痛了?
Let's go to the body.
我们进入身体
And that alternative channel-
那条新通路
the reason why it works because that's when we are drawing,
这个方法管用是因为当我们形成新通路时
that's when we are going to the body's natural ability to heal.
它通往我们身体的自然治愈能力
Most of the illnesses that we face,
我们患上的大部分疾病
the body has- most not all- has the compacity to heal itself.
不是全部 但大部分病身体都能自行治愈
Most of the cuts that you get-
大部分切伤的伤口
you don't need to do anything about it.
你不用管它
In fact,you shouldn't do anything about small cuts.
事实上 你不应该处理小伤口
You know play with it.Look at it.Touch it.
你不用弄它 看它 摸它
Just let nature take its course.
让自然的力量来治愈它
It will fix it by itself.Same with digestion.
它会自己愈合的 消化也一样
You don't need to think about digest...
你不用想着消化
The body has its own internal wisdom,its own internal healer.
身体有自己的内在智慧 内在医生
And this is exactly what happens
同样道理
when you go and you divert attention from
当你不再集中注意力想
"oh what I'm gonna do about it; What's happening;
"我该怎么消除它 怎么回事
it's so terrible; I hope I wouldn't feel this way;
太难受了 我不想这么难受
I hope I feel better soon;
我希望快点好起来
and why I'm feeling this way; what's the cause."
为什么我会这么难受 因为什么原因"
Somtimes it's important to do it and to analyze it,
有时候这样想它 分析它
to write about it,as opposed to to ruminate about it,
把它写下来很重要 但不要钻牛角尖
or to talk to someone about it,as opposed to ruminating about it
或者跟人谈谈 但不要钻牛角尖
But the most effective,
最有效的
in most situations is just to go to the body,bodily sensation.
在大部分情况下 就是马上想到身体的感觉
And be aware of it.Accept it.Don't try to fix it.
察觉它 接受它 不要尝试去治好它
Just let it be there and just observe it.
让它留在那里 观察它
And the,our internal healer will take care of itself.
我们身体内的医生就会治好它
The key,in order to become adept at it is to practice.
要熟练运用这种方法 关键是练习
It's to practice it.
练习
To do it over and over again,
一次又一次地练习
just like everything else that we've discussed in this class.
就像我们在课堂上讲到的其他方法一样
There are no quick fixes.
没有捷径
How do we practice it?
我们怎么练习?
First- and this is part of their 8 week program,
首先 这是书中的八周疗法中的一部分
which is what I'm doing right now- the first is body scan.
我现在也在练 首先是身体扫描
Become aware of your body
了解你的身体
just by lying down and thinking and observing.
躺下来 思考 观察
First of all,your foot and then becoming aware of your knee,
先从你的脚开始 然后了解你的膝盖
becoming aware of sensations in your crotch,
了解你胯部的感觉
becoming aware of sensations in your stomach.
了解你胃的感觉
Wherever it is.
每一个身体部位都是
Going through the whole body.
了解整个身体
And practicing it,becoming more aware.
多练习 多了解
And this is doing it in a cold state.
这是冷状态下的练习
This is doing it in the practice,in a simulator.
在模拟状态下的练习
Then when we are in a hot state,
当我们在热状态下
when we actually experience that emotion,that painful emotion,
当我们真正感受到那种痛苦情绪时
we are ready to go to it and we know what to do.
我们就准备好用这种方法 我们知道怎么用
Practice also means when we lose focus,we go back to it.
练习时 如果我们精神分散了 再集中起来
And that's the practice.
这是练习
The practice is not remaining completely centered for 30 minutes.
练习并不表示30分钟都要完全集中注意力
The practice is losing and coming back.
练习时 精神分散了 再集中
Losing focus and coming back again.
精神分散了 再集中
And then,also practicing in the real life.
然后在现实生活中也要练习
So whenever I feel stressed,merely going"OK.
所以当我感到压力时 我想"好的
So what's the physical manifestation of it?"
这种情绪引起什么身体反应?"
Now here we are talking about the emotions;
现在我们谈了情绪
we are talking about the body.
谈了身体
You can also practice by using cognitive reconstruction.
你们也可以用认知重建来练习
How? For instance.
怎样练习?举个例子
Let's say I'm thinking about a talk that I have to give tonight.
例如我想到今晚我要做的一个讲座
And I'm very nervous for it.
我感到很紧张
Large audience.Important audience.
很多观众 重要的观众
And every time I think of it,my initial inclination is stress.
每次想到这 我第一个反应就是紧张
And I get this adrenalin feel here and I don't feel good about it
我感受到这里的肾上腺素 很难受
Or the knot in my stomach.
感到我胃打了一个结
So how do I deal with it? Each time I think about it,I say,
我怎么办?每次想到这讲座 我就会想
"OK.Where am I feeling it in the body?"
"好的 这个身体反应在哪里?"
Another way of dealing with it is cognitively reconstructing it,
另一个方法就是用认知重建它
saying instead of stress,what a privilege.
不要觉得它是压力 觉得它是荣幸
Remember I told you that
我刚才说过
I had a very large client that I had to speak to,
我要跟一个很大的客户谈
I was very stressed about that talk.
我为这次演讲感到很大压力
And every time my mind went to stress,
每次我脑袋想到这压力时
within half a second I said,"no,it's a privilege.
马上我跟自己说"不 这是荣幸
It's so wonderful that I have the opportunity to do it."
我能有这样的机会做讲座真是太棒了"
Again,this is different from avoiding.
重申 这不同于逃避
This is different from repressing.
不同于抑制
There is a time to simply accept
有时候只需要接受它
and to give ourselves the permission to be human.
明白这是人之常情
However it's useless to just constantly ruminate about it
但是 苦苦思索这种情绪上是没用的
and simply strengthen the neural pathways.
只会加强这条神经通路
So this reaction of either going to the physical body
这种反应 或者专注于身体
or sometimes going to the cognitive reconstruction
或者专注于认知重建
can be very useful.
都很有用
Remember when we want change,
记得 当我们想改变时
we want to draw as much as possible on A,B and C-
我们要想到尽可能多的可能性
on affect,on behavior,and cognition.
想到情感 行为 认知的方法
And these are just two very helpful techniques.
这只是其中两个有用的办法
I use it constantly,whether it's going in the body
我经常用这种方法 或者专注于身体
or going in cognitive reconstructing.
或者专注于认知重建
Extremely helpful.
非常有用
Again the data shows how helpful it is.
有数据证明它多有用
Let's try it.Let's do a quick mindfulness meditation
我们也来做一次简单的正念冥想
and incorporating some of the ideas that I discuss now
运用我讲过的一些方法
and things that we've discussed in the past.
和我们以前讲过的一些内容
So sit comfortably in your seats as much as possible.
大家尽可能舒服地坐在座位上
Your back straight,
后背挺直
leaning on the back if that is more comfortable.
如果背靠着椅子更舒服的话 就靠吧
Elongate your neck as much as possible.
把脖子尽量伸长
Create a straight line in your upper body.
上半身形成一条直线
Plant your feet as comfortably as you can on the floor.
把脚尽量舒服地放在地板上
If there's a cross and you feel uncomfortable,uncross them.
如果觉得交叉着腿不舒服的 就放下来
And rest your hands either on your legs
可以把你的手放在腿上
or fold it however you feel comfortable.
也可以合起来 你觉得舒服就行了
And if you feel comfortable,close your eyes.
如果你觉得闭上眼睛舒服的 就闭上
Wherever your attention is now,
不管现在你的注意力在哪里
wherever your focus is now,bring it to your breath.
都把它集中在你的呼吸上
Breathe deeply into your belly
深深地吸进腹部
and then breathe slowly,gently,gracefully out.
然后慢慢地轻轻地呼出来
Take a deep breath and slow,gentle,quiet exhalation.
深吸一口气 慢慢地轻轻地呼出来
And repeat this a few times.
重复几次
If your mind wanders,
如果你精神分散了
simply,gently bring it back to the breath and practice.
慢慢把它集中回呼吸和练习上就行了
As you continue to breathe,shift your attention,
一边呼吸 一边转移你的注意力
your focus to your body-
转移到你的身体上
your feet,shins,your legs,your wrist,your belly,your back.
你的脚 小腿 腿 手腕 腹部 背
Just scan your whole body- your chest,neck,your head.
扫描你全身 你的胸膛 脖子 头
And find one area in your body that is slightly tense,
找出你身体感到微微紧张的地方
that you feel more than others,
比其他部位更紧张的地方
that is less relaxed than the rest of the body.
没有其他部位那么放松的地方
And whatever that part of the body is,
不管是哪个身体部位
shift your attention there and observe the discomfort,
把你的注意力转移到上面 观察不适
observe the tension.
观察这股紧张感
Just observe and accept it is.
观察它 接受它
Continue to breathe deeply
继续一边深呼吸
as you are observing that part of the body.
一边观察这个身体部位
And just look how interesting it is.
看看这多有趣
That you have that sensation there.
你那个部位有这样一个感觉
With each breath,embrace it.
每呼吸一次 就接受它
There's nothing right;
你的感觉
there's nothing wrong with how you feel.
没有对错之分
The feeling simply is.
它只是一种感觉
And continue with the breath
继续深呼吸
to breathe into that part and out of that part.
吸进那个部位 再从那里呼出来
Simply observing it,accepting it,being with it.
只需观察它 接受它 与它同在
Continue to be with that part of your body,
继续与你那个身体部位同在
with your breath and experience the experience.
一边呼吸 一边感受这种感觉
Whatever it is,it is.
不管是什么感觉 感受它
And then gently say goodbye to the focus on that particular part.
然后轻轻地把注意力从那个部位移开
Very gently,
轻轻地
because you just embrace it and return to your breath.
因为你已经接受它了 你要回到呼吸上
And with your breath,wash,cleanse your entire body.
用你的呼吸洗涤整个身体
Starting with your souls,
从你的灵魂开始
going all the way up to the top of your head.
从下到上 一直到你的头
And each breath introduces a deeper calm,
每次呼吸 平静加深了
deeper acceptance,deeper being.
接受加深了 存在加深了
Just experience,just feel the lightness,
体验 感受这股轻松感
the light that comes from acceptance,
因接受而带来的轻松
from our natural state of being.
自然状态下的轻松
Take another deep breath in.
再深吸一口气
Slow,gentle,quiet exhalation.
慢慢地轻轻地呼出来
And with the next exhalation,open your eyes.
呼完下口气 睁开你的眼睛
If the person next to you is asleep,again,
如果你旁边的同学睡着了
just gently nudge them or embrace them.
轻轻地推他们一下 或者抱一下他们
The effects of mindfulness meditation,mindfulness therapy-
正念冥想 正念疗法
it's quite literally mind boggling.
真的能改变我们的思维
What we are doing and what mindful therapy does
我们练习这种正念冥想时
is change our focus from doing to being.
我们的注意力从作为转移到了不作为上
How is that?
什么意思?
You see usually,usually when we experience something stressful,
通常当我们感到有压力时
or when our mind goes to a sad place,
或者当我们头脑陷入悲伤情绪时
our immediate reaction is how can I fix it.
我们第一个反应就是 怎么解决它
How can I fix it?
我怎么解决它?
And we try to fix it by thinking about alternative,
我们通过想其他办法来解决它
or by getting ourselves to feel better,
或者想办法让自己好受点
by thinking through the problem that we are facing.
或者分析我们面对的问题
Why? Because this fixing mind works.
为什么?因为我们这种解决问题的思维管用
I mean because of the fixing mind that we have science,
因为有解决问题的思维 我们才有科学
technology and progress;
才有技术和进步
and because of the fixing mind,the thinking mind,
因为解决问题 分析问题的思维
that you got in here.
你们才考进哈佛
You didn't get in here because you are a great meditator.
你们能考进来不是因为你们是成功的冥想家
You got in here because you did well in your tests.
你们能考进 是因为你们考试成绩好
You are able to solve problems well on the SATs.
你们能解答SAT上的问题
And that's a good thing.That's a important skill.
这是好事 这是重要的技能
But very often it's counter-productive
但通常它有反作用
when it comes to dealing with mental,psychological issues.
尤其是用它来处理思维和心理问题时
We gravitate toward it.We want to fix it.
我们会不由自主应用它 我们想解决问题
But very often it's counter-productive.
但通常会适得其反
Just like it would be counter-productive
同样会有反作用的
to try a meddle with the digestion that our bodies go through,
是我们想干预体内的
the digestive process.
消化过程时
It happens independent of us.
消化不受我们控制
If we try playing with it,open it,look at it,help it,
如果我们想左右它 看清它 分析它 促进它
we'll only hurt it.
我们只会伤害它
Why? Because the internal mind,the internal healer,
为什么?因为我们体内的主宰 体内的医生
the internal wisdom knows best to deal with certain things-
体内的智慧最擅长处理某些事
not everything,but certain things.
不是所有事 但是某一些事
Such as digestion.Such as very often,not always,
例如消化 还有通常的 不是所有的
but very often with mental afflictions,with painful emotions.
通常的精神问题 痛苦情绪
So we are moving,we are shifting our focus
所以我们要把注意力
from trying to fix to simply be with that emotion,
从解决这种情绪转移到与它同在
with that experience,with the manifestation of the pain.
感受这种痛苦的身体反应
In their book,William who teaches at Oxford:
在他们的书中 在牛津任职的William说
"Trying to get rid of depression in the usual problem-solving way
"想消除抑郁是通常的解决办法
trying to 'fix' what's 'wrong' with us,just digs us in deeper.
想解决不对劲的地方 只会让我们陷得更深
Rumination is part of the problem,not part of the solution."
苦苦思索是问题症结之一 不是解决方法"
Now the emphasis here is on rumination.
这里强调苦苦思索
It's not- and we've talked about it at all,
它并不等同于…我们之前谈过
it's not like if you write in your journal,it's not helpful.
它并不等同于写日记 它是没有益处的
It's good for you to write about issues
把你面对的问题写进日记里
that you are dealing with in your journal.
是有益于你的
It's good to talk to a very close friend.
和亲密朋友谈谈 是有益于你的
But just rumination,
但如果钻斗角尖
going over the same scenario over and over again.
一次又一次地思索这个问题
Ruminating about it,trying to fix it very often makes it worse.
苦苦思索它 想解决它 通常会使它恶化
And we would be better off just going to the emotion,
如果我们只是感受这股情绪
going to the physical manifestation.
感受身体反应 反而会更好
Try it.See what's right for you.
大家试试 看哪种方法适合自己
It may be right for you to you know,
也许适合你的方法是
write half an hour on one occasion
找个时间写半小时
and then just meditate on it for 10 minutes.
然后冥想10分钟
Or it may be right for you to only write about it.
也许光是写更适合你
It's different for different people.
每个人的方法都不同
But what I'm doing here
我给大家讲这些
is I'm adding another tool to your psychological tool box.
只是希望教会大家另一个心理工具
And just like we can cognitively reconstruct,
例如我们可以借助认知重建
as opposed to seeing it as a threat,to see it as a challenge;
把威胁看成挑战
as opposed to seeing it as a threat,to see it as a privilege;
把威胁看成荣幸
as opposed to seeing it as a failure,
把失败
just to see it as a learning opportunity.
看成一次学习机会
We can also have emotional reconstruction,
我们也能情绪重建
where instead of just thinking and ruminating about it,
不要对情绪苦苦思索
we go to the experience.
而是去感受它
"With the shift trying to ignore or eliminate physical discomfort
"不再尝试无视和消除身体不适
to paying attention with friendly curiosity,
而是抱着关怀之心去关注它
we can transform- quite literally transform our experience."
我们就能真真正正地改变我们的感受"
I'm going to leave you today with a last tip.
今天我教大家最后一个方法
And this is something that is very important
这个方法很重要
and that I highly recommend doing- for all of you,no exception.
我非常推荐 你们所有人都要学 没有例外
What I highly recommend doing is breathing.
我非常推荐的方法是呼吸
It's very,very important to breathe.
呼吸很重要
And in fact,it's the one thing
事实上 它是唯一
that's common to all the mindful meditation practices
所有正念冥想的共通点
and something that you can introduce to your life-
你可以把它应用于生活中
of course I mean proper breathing.
当然我所说的呼吸是正确呼吸
Something that you can introduce to your life,
你可以应用到你的生活中
even if you don't meditate for 15 minutes or 45 minutes a day.
即使你没有一天冥想15分钟 或45分钟
What I'm talking about here is deep breathing.
我所说的呼吸是深呼吸
Because here is what happens:
因为现实情况是
in our modern world,we are mostly stressed and anxious.
在现代世界 我们经常感到紧张焦虑
As a result of this,our breathing becomes shallow.
因此我们的呼吸变得很浅
And as a result of shallow breathing,
因为呼吸很浅
when our breathing is shallow,
当我们呼吸浅时
we become even more stressed and anxious.
我们就变得更紧张焦虑
And we go into this vicious cycle,
我们就会陷入一个恶性循环
vicious downward spiral of the "fight or flight" response.
一个"或战或逃反应"的恶性循环
And that's how we go through most of our days.
我们平常就是这样处理的
Fortunately we can reverse this.
庆幸的是我们可以扭转这种循环
And we can reverse this very quickly.
我们可以马上扭转它
Because we also know that
因为我们还知道
calm and well being leads to deep breathing;
平静和健康促进我们深呼吸
and deep breathing in turn leads to calm and well being.
深呼吸又能反过来促进平静和健康
We can reverse the "fight or flight" response
我们可以扭转这种"或战或逃"的反应
and enter what Herbert Benson calls,
进入Herbert Benson所说的
the relaxation response within as little as three deep breaths.
放松反应 只需三个深呼吸的时间
We can introduce these three deep breaths
我们可以把这三个深呼吸的方法
strategically throughout the day.
有计划地应用在一天的生活中
Just before class starts; just when the class ends;
上课前 下课后
just when I wake up in the morning;
早上醒来时
or the last thing before I go to bed.
或者上床睡觉前
Three deep breaths,
三个深呼吸
strategic points through the day can transform a life.
有计划地按排到一天的时间点上 能改变你的人生
Andrew Weil,graduate of our medical school,
Andrew Weil 我们医学院的毕业生
now at the University of Arizona,in his wonderful CD,
现在任职于亚利桑那州大学 在他很棒的CD中
talks about breathing:
他这样说呼吸
"If I had to limit my advice on healthier living to just one tip,
"如果我只能说一条健康生活的建议
it would be simply to learn how to breathe correctly."
答案很简单 学习正确呼吸"
And that means breathing like a baby breathes.
这意味着 像婴儿一样呼吸
Into the stomach.
吸进腹部
I told you,I'm not going to teach you much new in this course.
我说过 这节课不会教什么新知识了
You know how to breathe.
你们都知道怎么呼吸
You learn how to breathe when you were born.
你们一出生就知道怎么呼吸
All we are doing now is chipping away the excess stone
现在我们要做的只是去掉多余的牵绊
so that you go back to your natural wisdom,your natural healer.
求助于你的自然智慧 自然医生
In a wonderful book,
在一本很棒的书里
Alia Crum's Dad- she did the article with Ellen Langer-
Alia Crum的父亲 她和Ellen Langer写了这篇文章
Thomas Crum gives some good advice about
她父亲Thomas Crum提了几个很好的建议
how we can reverse the "flight or fight" response.
如何扭转"或逃或战"反应
And one of the things that he advises-
他的其中一个建议
he says that each time you get to a red light,
就是每次遇到红灯
use it as an opportunity to breathe deeply-
把它当作一个深呼吸的机会
whether when you are walking and you get to a red light,
不管是走路 还是遇到红灯
or in the car.
或者在车里
Now in the past...I introduced it.
以前…我用过这种方法
In the past,every time I got to a red light,it was annoying,
以前每次遇到红灯时 都很烦躁
especially if the light had just changed from green.
尤其是刚刚从绿灯转成红灯时
Now whenever I get to a red light,
现在每次遇到红灯
it's an opportunity and I breathe deeply.
我都把它当作一个机会 深深呼吸
Introduce deep breathing to your life.
在生活中学会深呼吸
Just a few times a day.
一天几次
And that can have far-reaching consequences.
能产生深远影响
So I'll see you next week.
我们下周见
And until then,breathe.
在此之前 大家深呼吸
[Applause]
掌声